Inventory of the Great Britain Ministry of Information propaganda
Hoover Institution Archives
- Pamphlets and leaflets, 1938-1949
  - "U.S.A.: California" (Box 14)
  - "U.S.A.: Our Town," Harrison & Sons Ltd., 1942 (Box 12)
  - "U.S.A.: The Arsenal of Democracy," Harrison & Sons Ltd., 1942 (Box 12)
  - "U.S.A.: The Cities of the East," Harrison & Sons Ltd. (Box 12)
  - "U.S.A.: The Makers of a Nation,", 1941 (Box 11)
  - "U.S.A.: The Middle West," Harrison & Sons Ltd. (Box 12)
  - "U.S.A.: The Nation They Made,", 1941 (Box 11)
  - "U.S.A. Transportation, Harrison & Sons Ltd., London, 1942 (Box 14)
  - "U.S.A.," Harrison & Sons, Ltd. (Box 11)
  - "Uganda for Victory," Cockayne & Co. Ltd. (Box 1)
  - "Underground War in the West" (Box 10)
  - "Underground War" (Box 10)
  - "United States Navy and Army Insignia," H.M. Stationery Office, London (Box 2)
  - "Urgent For Women Only," Economic Information Unit and Central Office of Information (Box 8)
  - "Valka v Obrazech" ("War in Pictures") No. 24, 25 (Box 15)
  - "Valka v Obrazech" No. 26-28, 30 (Box 15)
  - "Valka v Obrazech" No. 31-35 (Box 15)
  - "Valka v Obrazech" No. 36-40 (Box 16)
  - "Valka v Obrazech" No. 41-43 (Box 16)
  - "Een Verhaal Van Twee Geblitze Steden" (Box 8)
  - "La Vérité Enchainée,", 1944 (Box 1)
  - "The Versailles Treaty," Ministry of Information, England (Box 8)
  - "La Victoria de Africa," Stevens & B. (Box 1)
  - "Victory in Africa" (Box 4)
  - "Victory in the Desert" (Box 12)
  - "Victory Is Vital! Germans Would Make West Africans Into Slaves" (Box 4)
  - "Victory Is Vital! Germans Would Rob West Africans of Their Produce" (Box 4)
  - "Victory Is Vital! Germans Would Treat West Africans Brutally" (Box 4)
  - "Vier Jaar Oorlog Op de Kaart" (Box 3)
  - "The Voice of the Nazi 7," Sinclair, W.A., England (Box 4)
  - "The Voice of the Nazi 8," Sinclair, W.A., England (Box 4)
  - "Volksgezonheid in Groot-Brittannie" (Box 17)
  - "Volunteers from Eire who have Won Distinctions Serving with the British Forces: A Preliminary list (Box 7)
  - "Volunteers from Eire Who Have Won Distinctions Serving with the British Forces: Revised List,", 1939-1944 (Box 7)
  - "Volunteers from Eire Who Have Won Distinctions Serving with the British Forces: Supplementary list," M&C Ltd., 1944 (Box 7)
  - "The War (British Army)" Hore-Belisha, H.M. Stationery Office Press, 1939 (Box 3)
  - "The War and the Coloured Races," Kellher, Hudson & Kearns Ltd., England (Box 3)
  - "The War at Sea," H.M. Stationery Office Press, 1939 (Box 3)
  - "The War at Sea," First Lord of the Admirality, H.M. Stationery Office Press, 1939 (Box 3)
  - "The War in China," Ministry of Information (Box 6)
  - "The War in the Pacific: Part I, the Setting of Operations," Ministry of Information (Box 7)
  - "War in Pictures," supplement, "His Majesty King George the Sixth", 1941 (Box 4)
  - "War in Pictures" No. 30, 34 (Multiple Languages) (Box 16)
  - "War in Pictures" No. 4 (Farsi) No. 4, 1940 (Box 16)
  - "The War in the Air," Secretary of State for Air, H.M. Stationery Office Press, England, 1939 (Box 5)
  - "War in the Air," Wood, Kingsley (Sir), H.M. Stationery Office Press (Box 3)
  - "War Job," George Pulman & Sons Ltd. (Box 9)
  - "A War of Siege," B.E.F Information Bulletin (Box 10)
  - "War Pictorial, The Trail of Rommel's Defeat," England (Box 12)
  - "War Pictures by British Artists, Newton, Eric (Box 6)
  - "War Pictures by British Artists, Wilenski, R.H. (Box 6)
  - "War Pictures by British Artists," Molesworth, H.D., Cockayne & Co. Ltd., London (Box 4)
  - "War Service Grants and Emergency Grants," Ministry of Pensions (Box 8)
  - "The War Situation, 16 November 1939," H.M. Stationery Office Press (Box 3)
  - "The War Situation, 18 October 1939," H.M. Stationery Office Press (Box 3)
  - "The War Situation, 2 November 1939," H.M. Stationery Office Press (Box 3)
  - "The War Situation, 26 October 1939," H.M. Stationery Office Press (Box 3)
  - "War Time Finance," Ministry of Information (Box 3)
  - "War Under the Sea" (Box 10)
  - "War Work," The Transval Chamber of Mines, 1943 (Box 13)
  - "The War," Chamberlain, Neville, H.M. Stationery Office Press, England, 1939 (Box 5)
  - "The War: British Reply to German Proposals," H.M. Stationery Office Press, 1939 (Box 3)
  - "Wartime Survivors of Air and Sea Disasters Were Saved by City Ambulance Services,", 1945 (Box 14)
  - "Waste Collection is Essential," Ministry of Supply (Box 5)
  - "Waste Collection is Now Compulsory," Ministry of Commerce, Northern Ireland (Box 4)
  - "We Kneel Only to Thee," H.M. Stationery Office, London (Box 4)
  - "We Shall Win Because-," Preez, J. du, Union Unity Truth Service, London (Box 2)
  - "Welcome! From Winston Churchill "(April 1944), Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "Welcome! From Winston Churchill (October 1943), Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "Welcome! From Winston Churchill" (December 1943), Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "Welcome! From Winston Churchill" (February 1944), Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "Welcome! From Winston Churchill" (January 1943), Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "Welcome! From Winston Churchill" (January 1944), Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "Welcome! From Winston Churchill" (March 1944), Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "Welcome! From Winston Churchill" (November 1943), Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "Welcome! From Winston Churchill" (Undated), Ministry of Information (Box 12)
  - "Welcome!" W.R. Royle & Son Ltd., England (Box 2)
  - "Wessyl Eurona Eurachine" (Box 12)
  - "West Africa Towards Victory" (Box 1)
  - "West Indies Towards Victory," Alabaster, Passmore & Sons Ltd., England (Box 1)
  - "What Britain Has Done," Fosh & Cross Ltd. / K.H.K., London, 1943 (Box 3)
  - "What Have I Got to Lose?" Brown, M.J., The Baynard Press, England (Box 4)
  - "What 'Haw-Haw' Did Not Say," Nottingham Evening Post, England (Box 4)
  - "What Is at Stake?" England (Box 2)
  - "What is the British Empire?" Angell, Norman (Sir), England (Box 2)
  - "What is the Difference between Germany and Great Britain?" (Box 6)
  - "What Our Allies Wear: The Free French," K.H.K. (Box 3)
  - "What the British Empire Has Done: Facts and Figures on the Empire at War," K.H.K., 1944 (Box 7)
  - "What the British Empire Has Done: The Far East," K.H.K. (Box 3)
  - "What the Red Cross and St. John Are Doing," The Fanfare Press, London (Box 8)
  - "What the Red Cross and St. John Does for the Sick and Wounded," The Fanfare Press, London (Box 3)
  - "What to Do about Gas," Ministry of Home Security (Box 3)
  - "What to Do if the Invader Comes" (in Welsh), Ministry of Agriculture and Fisheries (Box 3)
  - "What You Should Know about Invasion Danger," K.H.K. (Box 4)
  - "Wheels That Turn for Victory" (Box 11)
  - "When Germany Dictates a Treaty" (Box 8)
  - "...Where Bert Is or What Jane Is Doing...," Gibson, George, K.H.K. Ltd. (Box 6)
  - "The White Ensign" (Box 2)
  - "Who 'Owns' the British Empire?" (Multiple Languages), Angell, Norman (Sir) (Box 14)
  - "Who Wants the 'New Order'?" L.T.A. Robinson Ltd., London, 1941 (Box 3)
  - "Why Does the French Government Arrest and Punish Communists?" (Box 4)
  - "Why Is the British Commonwealth so United in the Present War," Mears and Caldwell, England (Box 11)
  - "Why is There a War?" Alabaster, Passmore & Sons, Ltd., England, 1941 (Box 5)
  - "Why the Dominions Entered the War," England (Box 3)
  - "Why Victory is Vital!" (Box 6)
  - "Why You Should Practise as a Midwife," Fosh & Cross Ltd., London (Box 14)
  - "Wiliyati Akhbar," His Majesty's Stationery Office, 1942 (Box 13)
  - "Wings of an Empire" (Box 12)
  - "Wings of Freedom," Harrison & Sons, Ltd., London (Box 5)
  - "Winston Churchill," Barker, Ernest (Sir), Ministry of Information, London, 1945 (Box 7)
  - "Winston Churchill,", 1944 (Box 1)
  - "Winston Churchill's Speeches" (in Serbo-Croatian), 1946 (Box 14)
  - "The Woman from Poland," Brown, W.J., Home Service of the B.B.C., 1941 (Box 9)
  - "Women at War, Their Future in Peace," Burrup, Matheison & Co., London (Box 14)
  - "Women's Royal Naval Service," S.P. & Co. (Box 4)
  - "Work! Vigilance!! Courage!!!" England (Box 4)
  - "Workers under Hitler's Heel," HWV Ltd. (Box 2)
  - "Workers under Hitler's Heel," Geroge Pulman & Sons Ltd., England (Box 2)
  - "Working after the Siren," The Ministry of Home Security, England (Box 5)
  - "Working Together for Victory" (Box 5)
  - "World's Sea Trade," H.M. Stationery Office, England (Box 5)
  - "You Can Fill That Gap," His Majesty's Stationery Office, London (Box 6)
  - "You Can Help Your Country," England (Box 4)
  - "You Make Them Fly Another Day," His Majesty's Stationery Office (Box 9)
  - "Young Africa Goes to School," British Information Services / F & C. Ltd., New York City (Box 6)
- Maps, Portraits, Postcards, and Stamps, 1938-1949
  Arranged alphabetically by format. Dates are given when they appear on the document, otherwise dates are supposed to be within the years of World War II.
  - Civil Defense Maps (Box Map case)
  - "Outline Maps of European Coastal Areas," Ministry of Information, 1943 (Box 11)
  - "Outline Maps of Mediterranean Coastal Areas," Ministry of Information (Box 11)
  - "Outline Maps of Pacific Areas," Ministry of Information, 1943 (Box 11)
  - "Outline Maps of U.S.S.R. Areas," Ministry of Information, 1943 (Box 11)
  - Map of Phillipines (Box 14)
  - Map of the Ledo Area and Kengtung Area (Box 14)
  - Map of the United States of America, H.M. Stationery Office, London (Box 14)
  - Map of Tokyo Area (Box 14)
  - Maps of European Areas (Box 14)
  - Portraits "Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth" (Box 16)
  - Portraits "His Majesty King George The Sixth" (Box 16)
  - Portraits (unidentified) (Box 16)
  - Portraits of British People of Interest (Box 16)
  - Postcards, Portraits of People of Interest (Box 18)
  - Postcards, Ground Forces (in Farsi, English) (Box 18)
  - Postcards, Air and Navy (in French, English) (Box 18)
  - Postcards, Military scenes (Box 18)
  - Postcards, Miscellaneous (Box 18)
  - Stamps (Box 14)
  - Stamps (in Farsi) (Box 14)